Guide to the Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson
1828-1970
1870-1940
GEN MSS 664
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
54.4
(134 boxes) + 12 art
The Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson contains correspondence, manuscripts, personal papers, and research files by, about, and relating to Scottish author Robert Louis Stevenson.
Beinecke, Edwin J. (Edwin John), 1886-1970
Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired through various gifts and purchases from Edwin J. Beinecke from 1949 to 1970.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile Papers in box 134 may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm for portions of the collection available from Access Services.
Associated Materials
Material related to Robert Louis Stevenson that was acquired by the library through sources other than Edwin J. Beinecke is located in the Robert Louis Stevenson Collection (GEN MSS 684).
Robert Louis Stevenson (1850-1894)
Robert Louis Stevenson was one of the most popular and prolific British writers of the late 19th century, the author of verse, novels, travel books, short stories, plays, and essays, including such titles as The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde and Treasure Island. There is considerable secondary literature on Stevenson, including book-length biographical studies, chronologies, and bibliographies. Summary information is available in the standard print and online biographical resources.
Scope and Contents
The Edwin J. Beinecke Collection of Robert Louis Stevenson, formed by Beinecke Library benefactor Edwin J. Beinecke, comprises the largest group of material by, about, and relating to author Robert Louis Stevenson in the world. In addition to Edwin J. Beinecke's research files, the collection contains correspondence, writings, documents, photographs, artwork, memorabilia, scrapbooks, and personal papers dating from 1828 to 1970, with the bulk of the collection dating from the 1870s through 1940s, and Stevenson's correspondence and writings dating from the 1870s to his death in 1894.
As George Leslie McKay notes in his preface to volume three of A Stevenson Library: Catalogue, Stevenson's "wanderings about the face of the earth" and "distances of thousands of miles" from friends and family, resulted in voluminous correspondence. The collection contains approximately 3,300 pieces of correspondence altogether, with 1,000 letters by Stevenson and 300 letters by his wife Fanny Van de Grift. The largest groups of Stevenson correspondence can be found for his parents, Thomas and Margaret Isabella Stevenson, editor Edward L. Burlingame, and friends Charles Baxter and Sidney Colvin. Other noteworthy correspondents include Stevenson's cousin Robert Alan Mowbray Stevenson, his stepchildren Lloyd Osbourne and Isobel Field, collaborator William Ernest Henley, authors J. M. Barrie, Henry James, Andrew Lang, and Charles Warren Stoddard, the publisher Charles Scribner, and artists who made representations of Stevenson during the last decade of his life, Will Hicok Low, Auguste Rodin, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, and John Singer Sargent. Given Stevenson's wanderings and distances from correspondents, not surprisingly, according to McKay, many Stevenson letters document "his health... what he ate and drank, the people he met... [his] states of mind, [and] the books he read and... wrote."
Series II. Manuscripts by Robert Louis Stevenson consists of writings and other materials, such as notes and lists, in Stevenson's hand. The collection contains drafts of "more than half the poems" to several collections of poetry, including both Underwoods (1887) and Songs of Travel and Other Verses (1896), and complete or partial drafts to several prose works, including Catriona (1893), The Ebb-Tide (1894), In the South Seas (1896) and St. Ives (1897). There are also portions to the last three chapters of Stevenson's popular Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde (1886).
Series III. Addition and Other Materials consists almost entirely of Stevenson related materials not documented in McKay's Catalogue. This includes the photographs, artwork, and memorabilia that came to the library in the early 1950s with the principal gifts of Edwin J. Beinecke's collection, as well as smaller gifts and purchases made through the 1960s. There are original photographs of Stevenson, family, and friends, many Stevenson homes and residences, and the areas in which he lived and travelled, as well as albums containing material relating chiefly to Stevenson's life in Samoa. Artistic representations of Stevenson include work by well-known artists working at the turn of the 20th century. Works include: oil and watercolor portraits by Girolamo Nerli and Percy F. S. Spence respectively; charcoal portraits by Nerli and John Singer Sargent; busts and reliefs by Gutzon Borglum, Allen Hutchinson, and Augustus Saint-Gaudens; and engravings, etchings, and woodcut and linoleum prints by Robert Bryden, Timothy Cole, Samuel Hollyer, Thomas Johnson, Joseph Simpson, and Samuel Johnson Woolf. In addition, there are original drawings and watercolors for book illustrations by Robert Browne, William Hole, George Varian, and R. Canton Woodville, as well as original drawings by James Renwick Brevoort and Erastus Salisbury Field.
Edwin J. Beinecke's research files contain correspondence and documents relating to his acquisition of Stevenson material. Volumes feature correspondence between Edwin J. Beinecke and his assistant, Gertrude Hills, and others, including book and manuscript dealers, publishers, libraries, and Stevenson scholars. Correspondents include Clayton Hamilton, Sanki Ichikawa, Archibald MacLeish, Vincent Starrett, and descendants of Stevenson's family and friends.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 185?-1953. II. Manuscripts, 1828-1960. III. Additions and Other Materials, 1876-1966. IV. Research Files, 1877-1970.
Authors, Scottish -- 19th century -- Archives; Photographic prints; Scrapbooks; Authors; Balfour, Graham, Sir, 1859-1929; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937; Baxter, Charles, 1848-1919; Beinecke, Edwin J. (Edwin John), 1886-1970; Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore), 1848-1922; Colvin, Sidney, 1845-1927; Field, Isobel, 1858-1953; Gosse, Edmund, 1849-1928; Hellman, George S. (George Sidney), 1878-1958; Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903; James, Henry, 1843-1916; Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912; Low, Will Hicok, 1853-1932; Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, 1848-1907; Sargent, John Singer, 1856-1925; Stevenson, Fanny Van de Grift, 1840-1914; Stevenson, Robert Alan Mowbray, 1847-1900; Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894; Stevenson, Thomas, 1818-1887; Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1843-1909
- Correspondence, 185?-1953; Series I; 9.17; (23 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. Correspondence is organized into four subseries: Letters by Robert Louis Stevenson, Letters by Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson, Letters to and about Robert Louis Stevenson, and Transcriptions.
  Scope and Contents
  The arrangement of the first three correspondence subseries largely preserves the arrangement documented in volumes three and four of George Leslie McKay's A Stevenson Library Catalogue. Letters described in volume six, the Addenda & Corrigenda, have been moved and interfiled in the appropriate Series I subseries. Letters are arranged alphabetically within each subseries. McKay numbers follow each name or folder heading in parentheses. The first heading, for example, is for Allen, Grant (2629).
  As McKay notes in the preface to volume three of the Catalogue (1956), Stevenson's "wanderings about the face of the earth" and "distances of thousands of miles" from friends and family, resulted in voluminous correspondence. The series contains approximately 3,300 pieces of correspondence altogether and 1,000 letters by Stevenson himself. The largest groups of correspondence can be found for Stevenson's parents, Thomas and Margaret Isabella, editor Edward L. Burlingame, and friends Charles Baxter and Sidney Colvin. The series includes a significant number of letters, approximately 300, from Stevenson's wife Fanny. Other noteworthy correspondents include Stevenson's cousin Robert Alan Mowbray Stevenson, his stepchildren Lloyd Osbourne and Isobel Field, collaborator William Ernest Henley, and authors J. M. Barrie, Henry James, Andrew Lang, and Charles Warren Stoddard.
  Many of Robert Louis Stevenson's outgoing letters bear marks, including dates, McKay numbers, and other numeric codes. Letters are also often accompanied by copies (fascimiles and photostats), transcriptions, printed vendor descriptions and materials, notes, and provenance tracings, such as bookplates and stamps. Some letters are bound with other material. In such cases, the volume is usually filed by the lowest McKay number. References are provided where appropriate.
  Letters by Stevenson often provide only a partial form of the recipient's name. The full forms of names listed below are based first on the established name headings in the Library of Congress Name Authority file and, when not found in the name authority file, on the headings in McKay's Catalogue. Some letters are identified in McKay as having been dictated to or drafted by others. This information has not been preserved in the folder list below. Letters lacking dates, for which dates have been supplied in McKay's Catalogue and/or penciled onto letters, are bracketed (e.g. [1887]).
  Many letters attributed to Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson can be found in the Letters by Robert Louis Stevenson subseries. References are provided where appropriate.
  The Letters to and about Robert Louis Stevenson subseries combines incoming and third party correspondence. In addition to letters by the family, friends, and authors already noted among the outgoing correspondents, there are letters here by publishers, which shed light on the publishing of Stevenson's writings, and artists, including Will Hicok Low, Auguste Rodin, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, and John Singer Sargent. In order to distinguish the incoming and third party correspondence, the names of recipients have been listed in folder notes.
  The Transcriptions subseries consists of typescript transcriptions of selected original letters from the first three correspondence subseries. The transcriptions were made in 1953 at the request of Edwin J. Beinecke.
  A small amount of correspondence by Robert Louis Stevenson and Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson not documented in McKay's Catalogue can be found in Series III. Additions and Other Material. Correspondence about Stevenson can also be found in Series III, and correspondence relating to Edwin J. Beinecke's research into and acquisition of Stevenson material can be found in Series IV.
  - Letters by Robert Louis Stevenson to
    - Allen, Grant (2629), [1887 August?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Angus, William Craibe (2630), [1891] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Archer, William (2631), 1888 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Babington, Maud (2632 and 7979), 1870, [circa 1881] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Baildon, H. Bellyse (Henry Bellyse) (2633-2635), [1891], 1894
    - Bain, James (7930-7931), [1887], undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Balfour, Jane Whyte (aunt) (7932-7934), [1850s] (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Includes letters in the hand of Margaret Isabella Stevenson
    - Balfour, Lewis (grandfather) (7934), [1850s]
    - Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew) (2636-2638), 1893-[1894?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Baxter, Charles (2639-2890 and 7935-7939), 1871-1894 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes letters by Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson and third party correspondence
    - Bishop, Rev. S. E. (2891), [1890?] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Blackmore, R. D. (Richard Doddridge) (2892), 1882 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bok, Edward William (7940), 1893 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Brinley, James (7941), 1894 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Browne, Gordon (2893), 1892 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Burdick, J. W. (7942), 1888 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Burgess, Mrs. (2894), [circa 1888 April] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore) (2895-2967 and 7943), 1887-1894 (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
    - Carruthers, Richard Hetherington (2968), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Cassell & Company (7944), [circa 1883] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Cedercrantz, C[onrad] (2969-2970), 1892 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chalmers, James (2971 ), [1890 October] (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons
    - Chatfield, Robert (2972-2973), 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      General note
      Includes photostats of original letters held in Mitchell Library, Sydney, Australia
    - Chatto, Andrew (2974 and 7945-7946), 1885-1891 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Chatto & Windus (Firm) (7947-7950), [1887] (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Claxton, Arthur E. (2975 and 7958-7961), [1891?]-1892 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Colvin, Frances Fetherstonhaugh, Lady
    - Colvin, Sidney, Sir (2976-3031, 3033 and 7965), 1873-1879 (Box 1, Folder 27-33)
    - Colvin, Sidney, Sir (3034-3116 and 7971), 1879-1894 (Box 2, Folder 34-44)
    - Colvin, Sidney, Sir (7962-7964, 7966-7970 and 7972-7973), 1873-1888 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Cooper, William (3117), 1891 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Crockett, S. R. (Samuel Rutherford) (3118), [1894] (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Cunningham, Alison (7974), [circa 1873-1874] (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Cusack-Smith, Thomas Berry (3119-3122), 1892-1894 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Dick, James I. (3123 and 7975), [1887 June], undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Dobell, Horace (3124), 1866 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Dolman, Frederick (3125), [1884?] (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Dowson, Alfred (3126), [1884] (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Eeles, Charles G. S. (7976-7977), 1894 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Ehrich, Mrs. (3127), [circa 1887-1888] (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Includes fascimiles, third party correspondence, and clippings
    - Fairchild, Charles S. (3128-3139), 1887-1893 (Box 3, Folder 56-57)
    - Ferrier, Coggie (3140-3145 and 7978-7979), 1883-[1888] (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Ferrier, J. W. (James Walter) (3146-3149), 1872-[1880] (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Field, Isobel (3577a-3579), 1880-1894 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Forbes-Mitchell, William (7980), 1894 May 21 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Gilder, Joseph (3150-3152), 1887-1888
    - Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewert) (8400), 1885 January 6 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Gosse, Edmund (3153-3158 and 7982-8032), [1879?]-1894 (Box 3, Folder 63-64)
      Includes letters from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (8130-8135)
    - Haddon, Trevor (8033-8037), [1882-1884] (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider) (8038), [1891 June?] (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Harper & Brothers (3159), 1887 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Henderson, James (3160 and 8040), 1881, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Henley, William Ernest (3161-3173 and 8041-8043), 1878-[1892], undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Hytch, Mr. (8044), [1887?] (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Ide, Adelaide (8045), [1893 November?]
    - Ide, Henry Clay (8046-8047), 1881, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Ireland, Alexander (3174), 1882 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Japp, Alexander H. (Alexander Hay) (3175), [1881] (Box 3, Folder 73)
      Includes photostat of original letter held in Widener Library, Harvard University
    - Jenkin, Fleeming (3176-3177), [1881-1882] (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Jersey, Victor Albert George Child-Villiers (8048), 1893 February 3 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Jones, Humphrey Stanley Herbert (8049-8050), 1891 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Kelland, James (8051), [1887?] (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Kingero, Fujikura (3178-3179), [1877] (Box 3, Folder 78)
      Includes photostats of original letters presented by Sanki Ichikawa, Tokyo University
    - Lang, Andrew (3180-3182), [1886-1892] (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Lewis, ---- (3183), 1873 August 9 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Lindsay, Lady (Caroline Blanche Elizabeth) (3184), 1893 June 18 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - McClure, S. S. (Samuel Sidney) (3185-3186 and 8052), 1887, [1890?] (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Mackintosh, Jane Stevenson (cousin) (8053), [1887?] (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Magee, James (8054), 1889 June 19 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Malietoa, King of Samoa (3187), 1894 July 4 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - [Maona,----?] (3188), 1892 February 6 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - "Maryanne, Reverend Sister" (3189), 1889 May 22 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      Photostat
    - Marzials, E. (3190), 1884 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Mattos, Katharine de (3191-3192), [1874?], [1882] (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Melville, Andrew P. (3193), 1894 May 18
    - Meredith, George (3194), [1883?] (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Mew, Egan (8055), 1892 July 7 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Mitchell, S. Weir (Silas Weir) (3195), [circa 1887] (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Mitchell & Baxter (3196), 1893 August 6
    - Mobray, John T. (3197-3199), 1887 -1888 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Montagnon, Mabel S. B. (8056), 1886 October 5 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Mulligan, James H. (8057), 1894 October 4 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - New York Herald Tribune (3200), 1882 October 16
    - Niles, Thomas (3201), [1885?] June 6 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Norman, Henry (3202), 1885 November 12 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Osbourne, Lloyd (3203-3211), [1880]-1890 (Box 4, Folder 98)
      Includes note from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (3722)
    - Otis, A. H. (8059), 1889 June 15
    - Paget, Violet (3212), [circa 1885] (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Palmer, John Williamson (3213), 1886 February 13 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Payn, James (3214-3216), 1882-[1893] (Box 4, Folder 101)
      Includes facsimile of original 1882 letter held in Huntington Library and third party correspondence
    - Pennell, Joseph (8060), [circa 1884-1885] (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Pilsach, Baron Senfft von (3217-3218 and 8061), [1891]-1892 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Pollock, Walter Herries (3219), [188-] (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Pratt, Charles (8062), 1886 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - R. & R. Clark (Firm) (7951-7957), [1881-1887] (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Rawlinson, Mrs. (3220), [188-] (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Rearden, Timothy H. (Timothy Henry) (8063), [1881 May?]
    - Rick, Adolf (3221-3223), 1889-[1890] (Box 4, Folder 108)
      Includes printed ephemera (503-505)
    - Riding, Mr. (3224), 1894 November 4 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - [Roberts Brothers (Boston, Mass.)?] (8065), [1883 December?] (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Robertson, Charles Grant, Sir (3225-3230), 1881-1886 (Box 4, Folder 111-112)
      Includes letter from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (3724) and third party letter from William Fowler (4470)
    - Rogers, M. (8064), 1894 August 11 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Rosebery, Archibald Philip Primrose, Earl of (3231 and 8066), [1893] (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Sanchez, Nellie Van de Grift (3232), [1880 September?] (Box 4, Folder 115)
      Includes note from Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson (3730)
    - Scribner, Charles (3233-3268 and 8067), 1885-1892 (Box 4, Folder 116-117)
      Includes letters to Charles Scribner's Sons (3256-3268 and 8067)
    - Senfft von Pilsach, Baron
    - Sharp, William (8068), [1886?] (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Simpson, W. G. (Walter Grindlay), Sir (3269), [1884 April?]
    - Sitwell, Fanny (3270-3276 and 8069), [1873-1877] (Box 4, Folder 119-121)
      Includes photostats of original letters held at the National Library of Scotland
    - Sitwell, Fanny, [1873-1877] (Box 5, Folder 122-131)
    - Smith, Elder, and Co. (8070-8071), 1880-[1881] (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Speedy, Mrs. Thomas (3277), [1886?] (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Stedman, Edmund Clarence (8072), 1894 August 11 (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Stevenson, Fanny Van de Grift (3278-3310), 1882-[1894?] (Box 5, Folder 135-136)
    - Stevenson, M. I. (Margaret Isabella) (3311-3439), 1863-1894 (Box 6, Folder 137-148)
      Includes letters to Thomas Stevenson (3446-3447, 3466, 3482, 3499, and 3519)
    - Stevenson, M. I. (Margaret Isabella) (8073-8083), 1872-1890 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Stevenson, Thomas (3440-3481), 1854-1886 (Box 6, Folder 150-152)
    - Stevenson, Thomas (8084-8088), [1879-1885], undated (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Stevenson, Thomas and Margaret (3482-3549), 1863-1886 (Box 7, Folder 154-157)
    - Stevenson, Thomas and Margaret (8089-8093), [1880]-1886 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Stevenson, Robert Alan Mowbray (3032, 3550-3571, 8094-8095 and 8401), [1864?]-1894 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Stoddard, Charles Warren (3569-3571, 6665 and 6993), 1880 (Box 7, Folder 160-161)
    - Storrs, Ethel H. (3572), 1894 February 26 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Strong, Austin (3573-3577 and 8096-8098), 1892-1893 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Strong, Isobel Osbourne (3577a-3579)
    - Strong, J. D. (Joseph Dwight) (8099), [1880 December?] (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Symonds, John Addington (3580), 1888 November 11 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Salson, Tati (3581), [1888-1889?] (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Taylor, Ida Ashworth (8101-8102), [1886?], 1891 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Taylor, Theodosia Alice Spring-Rice, Lady (3582 and 8100), [circa 1885-1887] (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Tennyson, Mrs. Lionel (8103), 1887 December 24 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Thomas, Fred (nephew) (3583), 1887 October 31 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Thurston, John B. (John Bates), Sir (3584), [1892?] (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - The Times (3585 and 8104), [1892] (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Traquair, Henrietta (cousin) (3586-3588), 1868, 1871 (Box 7, Folder 173)
      Includes photostats
    - Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, Sir (3589-3590 and 8402), 1885 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Van de Grift, Esther Keen (3591-3593), 1888 (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Van de Grift, Jacob (3591), [1880 July] (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Watson, Rosamund Marriott (3594), 1893 June 30 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Weyman, Stanley John (8105-8106), 1893-1894 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Whyte, Alexander (8107), [1883?] (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Williams, Dora Norton (3596-3598 and 8108-8110), [1880]-1894 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Williams, I. (8111), [circa 1887-1888] (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Williams, Virgil (3595), [circa 1881 June] (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Williamson, R. (8112), [circa 1885-1887] (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Wilson, Lewis Henry Balfour (8113-8115), 1893-1894 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Wilson, William Frederick (8116), 1893 October 18 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Wise, H. B. (8117), 1894 March 21
    - Wister, Owen (8118), [1888] (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Unidentified (3599-3606, 8119-8125 and 8403), [1865-1894], undated (Box 7, Folder 187-188)
  - Letters by Fanny Van de Grift Stevenson to
    - Allman, Mrs. (8126), [1887 May] (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Baxter, Charles (3607-3635), [1882]-[1893]
    - Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore) (3636), 1887 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Chatto & Windus (Firm) (3637), 1887 January (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Colvin, Sidney, Sir (3638-3694), 1884-1898 (Box 8, Folder 192-193)
    - Ferrier, Elizabeth Anne (3695), [1895] February 26 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Field, Isobel (3831-3832 and 8163-8181), undated (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Forman, W. Courthope (3696), 1900 April (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Gosse, Edmund (8130-8134), [1884]-1894
    - Gosse, Ellen Epps (8135), [1882?] March 16
    - Hardy, Mrs. Thomas (3697-3700), [1885-1886] (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Henley, Anna Boyle (8136-8138), 1912 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Henley, William Ernest (3701-3720), [1881-1887] (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Ireland, Alexander (3721), [1884 February] (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Mulligan, James Hilary (8139), [190-?] (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Osbourne, Lloyd (3722), 1890 September 29